<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hematological malignancies on Russell E. Lewis</title>
    <link>https://russlewisid.com/categories/hematological-malignancies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hematological malignancies on Russell E. Lewis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 14:15:59 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://russlewisid.com/categories/hematological-malignancies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Changing Landscape of Hematological Malignancy Treatment:</title>
      <link>https://russlewisid.com/talk/targeted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://russlewisid.com/talk/targeted/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prognostic Aspergillus Models with Leukemia Sequencing</title>
      <link>https://russlewisid.com/project/bakeoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://russlewisid.com/project/bakeoff/</guid>
      <description>Polymorphisms in genes encoding fungal pattern recognition receptors (PRRs) of the innate immune system are associated with increased risk of invasive aspergillosis (IA), but incorporation genetic risk factors in clinical decision making remains limited. We propose to develop a combined clinical/genetic risk model suitable for accurately predicting an individual patient&amp;rsquo;s risk for developing IA within 60 days of admission for chemotherapy for acute myeloid leukemia/myelodysplastic syndromes (AML/MDS). We will develop a clinical risk model from a large data registry of 788 patients over 2,713 hospital admissions (2007-2020) for AML/MDS treatment that was associated with a 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing drug interactions with targeted chemotherapy</title>
      <link>https://russlewisid.com/blog/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://russlewisid.com/blog/social/</guid>
      <description>Brüggemann RJ, Verheggen R, Boerrigter E,Stanzani M, Verweij P, Blijlevens NMA, Lewis, RE. Management of drug-drug interactions of targeted therapies for haematological malignancies and triazole antifungal drugs. Lancet Haematol 2022;9:e58–e72. Available at: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S2352-3026(21)00232-5.
Abstract Over the past 10 years, the number of targeted therapies for haematological malignancies has substantially increased, and many new drugs have entered the market. Many of these therapies have shown improved disease-free survival and reduced toxicity compared with existing treatments, especially in older patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early low-dose CT plus pulmonary angiography to improve the diagnosis of aspergillosis</title>
      <link>https://russlewisid.com/blog/fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://russlewisid.com/blog/fonts/</guid>
      <description>Stanzani M, Sassi C, Lewis R, . Early low-dose computed tomography with pulmonary angiography to improve the early diagnosis of invasive mould disease in patients with haematological malignancies: A pilot study. J Infect 2021; 83:371–380. Available at: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2021.06.019.
Abstract High-resolution computed tomography (CT) is an essential diagnostic tool for invasive mould disease (IMD) in patients with haematological malignancies but is infrequently performed in the first 72 h of neutropenic fever until after chest X-ray (CXR).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy for the treatment of lymphoid malignancies-is there an excess risk for infection?</title>
      <link>https://russlewisid.com/blog/evergreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://russlewisid.com/blog/evergreen/</guid>
      <description>Gudiol C, Lewis RE, Strati P, Kontoyiannis DP. Chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy for the treatment of lymphoid malignancies: is there an excess risk for infection? Lancet Haematol 2021; 8:e216–e228. Available at: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S2352-3026(20)30376-8.
Abstract Therapy with genetically engineered chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cells targeting the CD19 antigen is promising for a number of refractory or relapsed B-cell malignancies. Information on the infectious complications of this immunotherapeutic strategy is scarce and difficult to interpret, as many factors influence infection incidence and outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
