<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent publications on Russell E. Lewis</title>
    <link>https://russlewisid.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent publications on Russell E. Lewis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://russlewisid.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is timing everything? A Bayesian meta-analysis of the prognostic and diagnostic utility of bloodculture time-to-positivity (TTP) and differential time-to positivity (DTP) for bloodstream infections</title>
      <link>https://russlewisid.com/blog/eccmid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://russlewisid.com/blog/eccmid/</guid>
      <description>Zaghi I, Sambri V, Lewis RE. 32nd European Congress of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases, Lisbon, Portugal. Abstract 01824 Poster is available to download here
Abstract Background: Time to positivity (TTP) and differential time-to-positivity (DTP) of central line vs. peripheral cultures are surrogate indicators for microbial inoculum and frequently investigated as prognostic or diagnostic markers in patients with bloodstream infections (BSIs). However, evidence concerning the prognostic or diagnostic utility of TTP and DTP is conflicting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing drug interactions with targeted chemotherapy</title>
      <link>https://russlewisid.com/blog/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://russlewisid.com/blog/social/</guid>
      <description>Brüggemann RJ, Verheggen R, Boerrigter E,Stanzani M, Verweij P, Blijlevens NMA, Lewis, RE. Management of drug-drug interactions of targeted therapies for haematological malignancies and triazole antifungal drugs. Lancet Haematol 2022;9:e58–e72. Available at: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S2352-3026(21)00232-5.
Abstract Over the past 10 years, the number of targeted therapies for haematological malignancies has substantially increased, and many new drugs have entered the market. Many of these therapies have shown improved disease-free survival and reduced toxicity compared with existing treatments, especially in older patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early low-dose CT plus pulmonary angiography to improve the diagnosis of aspergillosis</title>
      <link>https://russlewisid.com/blog/fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://russlewisid.com/blog/fonts/</guid>
      <description>Stanzani M, Sassi C, Lewis R, . Early low-dose computed tomography with pulmonary angiography to improve the early diagnosis of invasive mould disease in patients with haematological malignancies: A pilot study. J Infect 2021; 83:371–380. Available at: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2021.06.019.
Abstract High-resolution computed tomography (CT) is an essential diagnostic tool for invasive mould disease (IMD) in patients with haematological malignancies but is infrequently performed in the first 72 h of neutropenic fever until after chest X-ray (CXR).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy for the treatment of lymphoid malignancies-is there an excess risk for infection?</title>
      <link>https://russlewisid.com/blog/evergreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://russlewisid.com/blog/evergreen/</guid>
      <description>Gudiol C, Lewis RE, Strati P, Kontoyiannis DP. Chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy for the treatment of lymphoid malignancies: is there an excess risk for infection? Lancet Haematol 2021; 8:e216–e228. Available at: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S2352-3026(20)30376-8.
Abstract Therapy with genetically engineered chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cells targeting the CD19 antigen is promising for a number of refractory or relapsed B-cell malignancies. Information on the infectious complications of this immunotherapeutic strategy is scarce and difficult to interpret, as many factors influence infection incidence and outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
