<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Current projects on Russell E. Lewis</title>
    <link>https://russlewisid.com/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Current projects on Russell E. Lewis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://russlewisid.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Developing time to blood culture positivity (Tpos) as a pharmacodynamic biomarker</title>
      <link>https://russlewisid.com/project/giraffes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://russlewisid.com/project/giraffes/</guid>
      <description>Project website: www.acuteblood.com
PI: Irene Zaghi, M.D. Recipient of the 2022 ESCMID Young Investigator Award ESCMID research award link The effectiveness of antibiotic therapy in critically-ill patients with sepsis is often compromised by highly variable pharmacokinetics that can lead to subtherapeutic exposures and treatment failures, especially in the management of infections caused by multidrug resistant Gram-negative bacteria. Pharmacometric model-informed dosing and therapeutic drug monitoring (TDM) have been advanced as strategies for individualising antibiotic dosing in critically-ill patients, but the availability of these tools and expertise for implementation (especially for newer antibiotics) is often not available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prognostic Aspergillus Models with Leukemia Sequencing</title>
      <link>https://russlewisid.com/project/bakeoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://russlewisid.com/project/bakeoff/</guid>
      <description>Polymorphisms in genes encoding fungal pattern recognition receptors (PRRs) of the innate immune system are associated with increased risk of invasive aspergillosis (IA), but incorporation genetic risk factors in clinical decision making remains limited. We propose to develop a combined clinical/genetic risk model suitable for accurately predicting an individual patient&amp;rsquo;s risk for developing IA within 60 days of admission for chemotherapy for acute myeloid leukemia/myelodysplastic syndromes (AML/MDS). We will develop a clinical risk model from a large data registry of 788 patients over 2,713 hospital admissions (2007-2020) for AML/MDS treatment that was associated with a 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting CRE infection after liver transplantation</title>
      <link>https://russlewisid.com/project/penguins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://russlewisid.com/project/penguins/</guid>
      <description>Giannella M, Freire M, Rinaldi M, Abdala E, Rubin A, Mularoni A, Gruttadauria S, Grossi P, Shbaklo N, Tandoi F, Ferrarese A, Burra P, Fernandes R, Aranha Camargo LF, Asensio A, Alagna L, Bandera A, Simkins J, Abbo L, Halpern M, Santana Girao E, Valerio M, Muñoz P, Fernandez Yunquera A, Statlender L, Yahav D, Franceschini E, Graziano E, Morelli MC, Cescon M, Viale P, Lewis R, Bartoletti M, Pascale R, Campoli C, Coladonato S, Cristini F, Tumietto F, Siniscalchi A, Laici C, Ambretti S, Romagnoli R, De Rosa FG, Muscatello A, Mangioni D, Gori A, Antonelli B, Dondossola D, Rossi G, Invernizzi F, Peghin M, Cillo U, Mussini C, Benedetto FD, Terrabuio DRB, Bittante CD, Toniolo ADR, Balbi E, Garcia JHP, Morrás I, Ramos A, Cruz AF, Salcedo M.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
